[音乐]
- 大家好！- 大家好！
你好 Sebastian! 我是 Astro！
能请到 Astro 我感到非常荣幸 请允许我
介绍我最好的 以及长久的朋友 -- Astro Teller
名字同高贵的领主一样享誉
Google X 的负责人 现在叫 X lab
一个极具天赋的很棒的人
- 你们当中的一些人可能认识他 欢迎他的到来 - 谢谢
我第一个非问不可的问题是
这件夹克是怎么回事？
我今天早上穿的就是这件
事实上我有这件夹克 我认为
有人可能想整蛊我
他们给了我这件夹克 我想
Craig Barrett 他当时也在
Alphabet 工作 一个合适的夹克不是
r2d2的夹克 它是一个 wiki 夹克
所以他喜欢上了这里斜跨的弹夹
也喜欢拉起全是毛的帽子
他说 没门！我不能穿那个去
因为我们要在那边花费一天
我看到一起类似事件
他没有穿那件衣服
你知道的 我只是想
这有点坡脚 我要穿我的 r2d2 夹克
所以 我的意思是我去演
“星球大战” 但我不是说我要在里面做超级明星
我只是想为喜欢的事工作一天
我不知道 然后我来工作了
我猜我只是很喜欢当一个机器人
你猜你是机器人？
- 开个玩笑 - 但是你成为我们的招聘合作伙伴
是的 我们做到了！
太好了！
在我被解雇之后 我思考了一段时间
我认为在硅谷工作是最好的选择
不 这完全是个巧合
你们在招聘什么？
我们招聘的职位有很多
显然 我们在招聘机器人专家
我们十分关心机器学习
我们在 X labs 做的很多工作就是系统整合
我们并没有做很多基础性科学工作
但是我们解决了很多以前未解决的问题
所以 很多复杂的迭代系统集成性工作我们已经在做了
有时候 他们所制定的传统版本需要被用不寻常的方式整合起来
你得到它 尝试它 并证明你做错了
然后你做了一个新的设计 再尝试
我想 这是 X labs 的项目的一般模式
所以 这里的人很擅长这个
你觉得 50 年后 世界会变成怎样？
棒极了！我们走吧！
我不想严格按照你的问题 回答未来 50 年会发生什么
因为我认为 20 年后世界就会大变样了
会变得更糟吗？
我确信喜忧参半 我认为很大概率上在大多数好的地区会让人激动
我相信中间的道路不会明确
很多人觉得会有世界范围的核战争 导致核冬天
我不知道 我认为这个世界的积极因素
比我们以为的更多
世界会走过一个非同寻常的20年
这就是说 我认为人们倾向于高估短期的技术进步和改变速率
未来3年内 他们认为世界将和现在变得大不相同
但他们低估了在中期 也就是10~20年的变化
我想 我们都很难想象会有多大不同
我的经验告诉我 从现在起的20年 大概就像过去的100年
所以 你能想象过去100年的变化和接下来20年的变化么
我认为这是一个较为现实的估计 估计未来的世界会有多大不同
这意味着人们需要学习很多东西
是的 我认为我们的社会还没有适应如此快的变化速度
你身上有一件事让我印象深刻
就是你对于创新 以及恐惧、失败等事情的态度
当你解雇一些人的时候 你会庆祝一番 是这样吗？
是的 我是说 我不确定我们会让其他人去做什么。
可是有时候在一些情况下
我们帮助人们
去一个对他们来说更好的平台
我至少说是提供一些机会给他们...
>> 释放他们 >> 绝对是
比如如你所知
苏西可以在另一些地方做的很棒
但是她现在所在的地方并不好 把这个告诉她
这对苏西的团队和我也有好处
对她自己也有好处
当然不告诉她
让她承受当她的能力出色到
可以完成更好的任务时
却还要一直去做不出色的事
这并不是在帮任何人忙 特别对苏西而言
>> 顺便说一下 你对我们所有的学生都这样
>> 释放所有的人的潜力？
>> 你可以让他们所有人毕业。>> 是的
我对我们所有的项目都做同样的事
>> 是的 斯坦福还是 不记得这些了..
我们送走每个学生时
所拥有的美好的时光 >> 我想起
他的父母与他一起乘电梯过来
>> 这就是为什么我们
称之为毕业项目
X 不会让他们觉得
被踢出了伊甸园 他们
会有一点背井离乡和
充满希望上大学的感觉 >> Steve Blankie，
前美国宇航员 想问一个问题
我也想问你同样的问题
我想让你
回到18岁 当你刚进入大学
你对自己有什么建议
>> 你知道的
我经常想的事情之一就是
如果我能重回 18 岁并改变一些事情
哪怕只是一小段时间
但它实际上对我来说很多 而不是很少
我是一个大三学生 也许有二十来岁
大概在斯坦福大学
我弟弟刚来斯坦福大学
他是新生
他正在读物理学学士
但他实际上花了更多的时间在演艺事业上，
成为一个舞台人物
而不是攻读他的物理学学位
我正好认识
他的导师：Winter Meade
一次表演之后 Winter来找我并说
你在剧院会更加成功
你真的应该加入一家公司去做点什么了。
我说 哦不
我真的很忙 我有一堆借口
我当时真的很忙
那不是我说不的理由 我很害怕
我只是不知所措
我想可能是因为那对我不是真的重要
从那以后我很后悔
不是因为我想进剧院 这只是很困扰我
这是少数几件我生活中没有做的事
因为我害怕
我也知道我没做它是因为我害怕
自那以后我想 我不再做那个了
我可以以各种各样的原因失败
但我不会再失败了
因为我害怕去尝试
>> 所以当你害怕时 你会这么做？
>> 是的 我事实上抗拒恐惧...
>> 你怎么来开车 >> 事实上我不怕追踪一个车
但是我还没有闯过红灯
>> 不同的故事 你已经做了
在硅谷中都是一项
令人难以置信的工作了
你像魔术师一样将气球放入平流层
你在 X 中做过自动驾驶
或者其他的什么
什么驱动着 X 这艘大船
也许我可以拿我的一点点信用
但是你的秘诀是什么 看起来感觉很不真实
这个组织发展并成熟 坦白来说
规模更大而且能够与时俱进
你怎么保持你的
创新基因持续呢
>> 我想到很多在X中的矛盾和难题
其中的一些相当简单
其实一些则并不简单
但是 例如
我们必须有极为乐观的态度
或者我们不会尝试所有的事
但是如果你
只是让人们肆意乐观
那么出门 疯狂去吧 越疯越好
没有限制 你不会得到好的结果
所以必须有一种
令人沮丧的偏执和怀疑态度
才能平衡这种乐观
如果你想得到你想要的
你必须保持平衡
但是那不是我们拥有的唯一一种紧张局面
你知道另一种
你可以说乐观将会
支持 X 的结构　或者你想否定它
因为 X 中的官僚主义
所以 我们想要在
正确的时间对项目进行正确的帮助
详述它们或进行帮助
在他们完成项目时
保证不偏离正确的轨道
在最佳的情况下 这
很棒 当然它听起来真的
很棒 像我刚刚说的那样 但是如果
它做的不好 那么一定看起来像
官僚主义的项目负责人 以及
他们有的时候会告诉我
官僚体制是最后一个我
想制造的 所以这是另一个
例子 那些无结构的
也是无意义的 所以我们仅仅是
风险投资者 我们只是给予
人们金钱并走开了
那么这对于我们做这件事是没有任何意义的
但是如果我们紧紧勒住他们
如果我认为我知道如何把他们的工作
实现的比他们还好 那我们中的一个肯定是多余的
看起来是一个糟糕的计划 所以轻微的接触
是另一个例子
两个极端都不好
中间的平衡点
是我们一直寻找的正确的地方
>>很多学生和
伙伴来找我 我认为超过20个国家
这很令人惊讶 包括了
像约旦、爱沙尼亚这些地方 硅谷的魔力是什么
对于不同国家的人
你又能把什么带回家
>>如果说这里的水有什么东西的话
我认为可以肯定的是人。
>> 事实上
我不是真的建议你把水带回家
你是知道的
其中一种方式 尽管不是我喜欢的措辞
但我已经听了很多次的
是一种开拓性的创造文化
所以这并不是我要带回家的
但是我认为你可能已经听到了很多次
其中有一种方式我可能更喜欢
请乐观的拥抱失败
所以一家韩国的报纸
问我怎么才能让
公司在韩国做的更好
他们真的是害怕去承担风险因为
他们可能会看着很糟
我不知道这是否是真的
但是这是我在昨天早上
请一位记者带给韩国公司的建议
我们并不是想在硅谷看到这不好的结果
但是我认为并不全都是这样
但是 我愿意现在看起来是愚蠢的
如果是从长远来看
会赢得胜利的话
我认为这是一个时间差异
如果你明白并可以理解学习的本质
是对错误保持开放的心态
学习是导致你获胜的
最强大的力量
然后你渴望错误 并重新开始
迫不及待的去尝试新事物
不论在短期内你看起来是如何的不完美
都没有关系
因为你不愿意输掉的时间范围更长
并且我认为
尽管在硅谷有一种追求速度的文化
但是我相信人们
试图让自己变得更好的
时间维度可能会拉的更长
这可能也是秘诀
我们有麦克风
我想要给观众几个开放问题
你们可以像以前一样
两个麦克风排队
我有一个问题
希望你告诉我们你儿子的故事
>> 他指的是我儿子一年多以前
已经完成他的第一个纳米学位了
他的名字叫 Griffin teller
他完成的是
计算机科学导论
他很喜欢这个
他在12岁的时候完成它的
他十分努力的完成它
一点点小的挣扎不是恐惧
即便是机器学习课程
我刚刚..
上周晚餐告诉他
他说
那门课真的蛮艰难的
And I went home and said, you know,
我回家说 你知道的 Griffin
Griffin, you're going pretty slowly
你通过它花了很久
Sebastian说
这个课程真的很难
你想要寻求帮助吗？你想要换一个简单的嘛？
他喜欢这个 不 不 我选了这门了 我只是...
我必须坚持下去
每到下一个阶段 都要学一大堆额外的数学课程
他现在13岁，所以..
但我非常感谢 Udacity
因为Griffin是个勇敢的男孩
他很努力工作 也很专注
但这本身就是在
这绿房子里说
实际上并不是这样的
我不认为这是一个意外
他不是在做化学或者物理或者历史
没有一个支持他的平台
Udacity实际上已经
给了他正确的结构
所以他必须努力
他可以自学
这对他意义重大
这也是我今天为什么在这
>> 是的 我们有20多个招聘人员
我想你应该把他带到这里和他们聊聊
>> 棒极了 否则就会超过学费了
让我们从中间开始吧
>> 你好 Teller先生
可以分享一些关于对冲基金在
强化学习中的用法么？
>> 强化学习的哪个领域？
>> 对冲基金或财务。 >> 对冲基金。
我不确定强化学习是...
一个问题 让我更全面的回答你的问题
我相信目前在许多领域
应用机器学习的方式
那么人类所构成的
问题将会结束 它会消失
你知道的 10年或20年
它不会发生在一夜之间
事情开始是这样
你可以看到它
发生在对冲基金领域
这正是机器学习问题的
本质所在
现在它往往不会像机器学习一样
你知道深度网络和强化学习
以及其他一些工具
有时不会像问题被问道
但是当您在任何领域中
进行任何形式的端到端学习时
你基本上都会离开系统
这正是在学习
the learning, more of the decomposition
更多的是将问题分解到计算机
到学习系统
这是任务的一部分————
将数据功能化 分解问题
这是人类以前做的
所以我认为这些行为是
我们要看到更多的东西
更多的是开始问问题
和计算机基本结构
相关的问题
这实际上就是在解决问题
而对冲基金绝对是发生这种情况的领域之一
>> 好的 谢谢
>> 你可以总结下你的失败观么
在失败上 失败的越快 学习的越快?
learn faster? >> Yes, I mean fail fast is
>> 是的，我的意思是，快速失败是口头上的，应该是绕着山谷和其他地方快速抛出。
lip service, which is thrown around very
liberally all around the valley and
other places. And I think it largely does
我认为它在很大程度上不会知道人们想要什么。
not get people what they want. And so
所以这个术语-失败很快没有任何错误，但是50美元可以让你上公共汽车。
there's nothing wrong with the term
fail fast, but that and the dollar fifty
will get you on the bus. The problem is
问题是，正如失败快一样，你说的只是口惠，然后实际上是人们真实做的。
that, there's the lip service of whatever
you say, like fail fast, and then there's
the actual way that people behave. And
这些指针如此不同的原因在于你的组织中有阻力最小的情感路径。
the reason that those pointers are so
different, is because these are the
emotional paths of least resistance in
your organization. And you can say fail
你可以等到奶牛回了家才说快速失败，但是如果你惩罚被人，事实上，如果当他们失败时，你做了任何事积极回报他们，那么你说快速失败并不重要。
fast until the cows come home, but if you
punish people, in fact if you do anything
short of actively rewarding them when
they fail, it doesn't matter that you say
fail fast. So what do you mean it when
所以，当你再说快速失败时，你是在说什么呢？
you say fail fast. And so we have
当人们站起来时，我们的X项目有回报机制，他们说，这是我们刚刚跑的有价值的实验，以及，实验的结果是零假设，例如：我们不应该做这个。
mechanisms at X to reward people when
they stand up and they say, that was a
worthwhile experiment we just ran, and
the results of the experiment is the
null hypothesis, i.e. we shouldn't keep
doing that. Great, let's go on to the next
太棒了！让我们进入下一步。
one. You reward them in that moment, you
你在那一刻奖励他们，你不要惩罚他们在试验中所得到了0假设的结果。
don't punish them for admitting that the
result of the experiment was the null
hypothesis. That's often the answer when you
当你进行实验时，也很容易得到这个答案。
run an experiment. But that's not how
但这不是大多数公司的工作方式，这不是人们早上上班的感觉。
most corporations work, that's not how
people feel when they go to work in the
morning. They want to get an atta boy
他们想在伙伴中找到一个男孩，他们想从经理那里得到一个男孩，如果他们说了“我的程序没有起作用”而得到他，他们将不会再说了。
from their peers, they want to get an
atta boy from their manager, if they
can't get one by saying my thing didn't
work, they will not say my thing did not work.
嘿 Teller博士 谈到这个讲话
添加一个问题 登月是否可以解决
饥饿问题 我是说
我们是否可以使用技术
解决这些真实问题？ 就以饥饿为例
>> 当然 我还没有准备好
一个解决饥饿的方案
但是我不认为有问题可以阻碍有关登月的思考
至少我们会在X项目
中定义这种方式
一个月球探测器有三个基本元素：
这是一个真实的问题
你可以定义它 你想要解决它
正如你刚刚所指出的我们世界存在的
problem in the world. The second is you
一个巨大真实的问题 第二点是你必须要有
have to have a radical proposed solution
to that problem, not radical because you
一个激进的解决方案来解决这个问题，不激进是因为你想变得很酷，
找到那些很奇怪的点子，但是，去尝试一个新地方，
尝试人们没有尝试过的东西，这不仅仅是一个聪明的比赛，
其他每个人都想解决这个问题，但是更富勇敢和创新的内容聚焦于问题本身。
want to be cool and get cool points in
the world for having been weird, but in
the spirit of trying to go to a new
place, to try something that people
haven't tried, to not just be in a
smartness contest where everyone else
who's tried to address the problem, but
to be in more of a bravery and
creativity contest with the problem
itself. So that's the second thing, having
所以，这第二个事就是有一个彻底的解决方案。
a radical foreclosed solution. And then
然后第三个问题是，我们至少要定义它，但是我想有其他方法修补问题，但是在X项目，我们必须有第三个方面，让它成为一个探测器，你必须提出一些有突破性的技术或者提出的技术组合是一个突破，这将会使得这个听着像科幻小说的产品或服务可以解决这个问题。
the third at least as we would define it,
but I suppose there other ways of
dressing problems, but at X we would say
that the third aspect
that you have to bring in order for it
to be a moonshot, is you have to present
some kind of breakthrough technology or
proposed set of technologies which
brought together would be a breakthrough,
that would enable this science-fiction
sounding product or service that would
solve that problem. Put in that way,
以这种方式，没有理由利用这些工具还解决不了饥饿问题，我希望你能做这个。
there's no reason that you couldn't
solve starvation and hunger using those
tools, and I hope you do. >> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> You just described some of the criteria for
>> 你刚刚描述了一些好的项目的标准，但是项目从哪里开始，如何通过审查，并形成一个长期的项目。
what makes a good project， but where do
the projects come from originally and
how do you go through vetting
them， and forming like a more long-term
project. >> So I could imagine other ways of
>> 所以，我可以想象其他的做法，大概就是在X项目的这个感觉，在隐喻表上有一堆想法。
doing it, roughly the way it feels at X,
is there's a huge pile of ideas on the
metaphoric table. Anyone can put them on
任何人都可以把它们放到桌子上，顺便说一下，我们有一个机制，你们可以在我们的网站上提交：X项目的探测想法。
the table, and by the way, we have a
mechanism where you guys can submit on
our website: moonshot ideas to X.
We're very happy to take them from any
我们非常高兴可以带他们去任何地方，因为我们相信他们的想法，粗略的技术，确实是值得的但是他们还不能把这些变成真正伟大的事情。
in all places, because we believe that
ideas by themselves, raw technologies by
themselves, they worth something but
they don't reliably turn into something
great. That the work that's really
真正的特殊工作发生在这个想法之后。
special happens primarily after the idea.
So we have this huge pile of ideas on
所以我们在桌子上有这么多伟大的想法，这里没有一个实际的桌子，很多工作很快失败了，很多工作都是如何从桌子上挑选这些想法，并尽可能的将它们丢开，尽可能有效，但是要为了好的原因，而不是假的原因。
the table, there isn't an actual table
right, and then a lot of the fail fast, a
lot of the work is how do you pick
through all these things on the table,
and throw them away as fast as possible,
as efficiently as possible, but for good
reasons, not for fake reasons. f you're
你就像我不喜欢的那个，从桌子上拿开很简单，但是你没有真正为它附加价值，这不是一个好原因。
like I don't like that one, it's easy to
take it off the table, but you haven't
actually added any value, that's not a
good reason. If you pick one off the
如果你从桌子上挑了一个，你说，嘿，看，这违反了热力学第二定律。
table and you say, hey look, this one
breaks the second law of thermodynamics.
I think we can throw that one away
我认为我们可以把它丢掉而没有任何讨论。
without further discussion. Oh look, this
看吧，这是由难得矿素构成，是的，我们可以把那个丢开。
one is made of unobtainium, right, so we
can throw that one away. Sadly not all of
可悲的是，不是所有的这些都可以从桌子上轻易的移除，所以你要经常做真正的工作。
them can be removed from the table as
easily as those, and so you often have to
do real work. Sometimes you have to build
有时候你必须建立原型，你必须和那个处在生态系统中的人交谈，如果我们这么做的话会解决问题吗？
prototypes, you have to talk to the
people who act in that ecosystem and say,
if we built this thing would it solve
the problem? And then they say, not really,
然后他们说，不行，我们没有为了建立那个而花费大量时间和金钱，仅仅在最后发现，并没有真正解决这个世界上的问题。
well that's good to know, thank goodness,
we didn't spend a huge amount of time
and money building the thing, only to
discover at the end, that that wasn't
really going to solve the problem in the
world. So that is one of the main muscles
所以这是X的主要肌肉之一，你如何让人们感觉良好并把东西放在桌子上，最好这些事是发生在一次会议中，这已经在X中发生了几次了。当有人想从我这里或其他人那里获得印象分，只因为提出了一个美丽的想法，并在相同的会议中提出了，得到了两个印象分，这是快速失败。
at X, is how do you get people both to
feel good about throwing stuff onto the
table, and feel good about taking it back
off the table, and the best-case scenario,
which has happened a few times that X, is
when the both happen in the same meeting,
when someone gets a brownie point from
me or from others, for having brought up
a beautiful idea, and in the same meeting
throw the idea way, and gets two pieces
of brownie point, that's failing fast.
When they feel like they got brownie
当他们觉得因为把这东西放到桌子上而得到印象分之后，会在半个小时的会议中把它拿走。
points for putting on the table and
taking it off in a half an hour meeting.
>> So I was about to pass this question, but
>> 所以，我即将通过这个问题，但是当你还在说你明天不会后悔的时候，那我就应该过来了。
then when you said that don't regret it
tomorrow, that's why I came in here. >> Good.
>> 好。
>> So both of you are people who have
>> 所以你们都是那种每个人都希望在他们生活当中创造影响力的那种人。
created the kind of impact which
everyone here wants to create in their
lives. But my question is that, suppose
但我的问题是，假设你有一个像我这样的人，我明白了我的激情，这是我想要解决的问题；但在另一方面，我也要保持变化，我需要知道现在发生的事情，我需要阅读诸如科技博客、内参、商业内幕消息。这里每天会创造很多资源和很多信息，如果我每天花很多时间阅读这个，我就没时间解决我的问题，也没时间完成我的工作了。
you have a person like me, I have figured
out that this is my passion, this is the
problem I want to solve, but along the
side, I need to stay relevant, I need to
know the current affairs, I need to know
like read TechCrunch, wired, Business
Insider, there are like so many resources
and all of them creating so much new
information every day, that if I spend
time reading those, I won't solve my
problem. I won't be doing my job. So my
所以，我的问题是，如何遵循你的激情来安排你的时间并让自己不断提高。
question to you is, along with following
your passion, how do you spend your time
and keep yourself updated. >> So, both of
>> 所以，这个答案可能会受你们欢迎，但世界其他地方可不会。
these answers will be probably
popular with you guys, but not popular
with much of the rest of the world. But I
我对这两个都很强烈。
feel pretty strongly about both of them.
The first one is, I got lucky. I won't
第一个是，我很幸运。
speak for Sebastian, but I got lucky. And
我不会为塞巴斯蒂安说话，但我很幸运。
I hope that you guys are calibrated on
我希望你们是这样校准的，那些最成功的人通常工作的相当努力，他们有一些技能，不完全依靠幸运，也不相信拥有或获得很多幸运，就好像没有那么多幸运一样。
that, that the people who are the most
successful, usually worked fairly hard,
and they have some skill, that wasn't
entirely luck, but do not believe that
there is not a huge amount of luck
involved or hold yourself to a standard,
as though there were not a huge amount
of luck involved. It will drive you crazy
巨大的不公平会让你疯狂。
totally unfairly. The second thing is, I
第二件事，我不读大多数的商务书；我每周读经济学人，但我几乎不读新闻，尤其是最近的，这会让我疯狂。
don't read business books, actually
mostly, I read The Economist every
week, but I mostly don't even read the
news, especially now, it's driving me
crazy. You know what I spend time doing> I
你知道我花时间做了什么，我和人们交谈，我聆听他们说的。
talk to people and I really listen to
them. The things that I was describing
我是在说X项目是如何安排的，并不是从我读的商务书上获得，事实上，我管理这些人，我连驱动他们的微小事物都会关注。
about how X is set up, that's not taken
from some great business book I read, I'm
actually managing people, and I'm really
paying attention to what moves their
needle. It's like this observation is
这就像在旁边看着别人做，说，你这样做，你这样做。
just watching people and saying like, oh
I told you to do that and you're doing
this. Why are you doing that? You just go
你为什么要这样做？你只是去让他们做。
ask them. I have behaviors that you won't
你不会在商业书籍里面看到我的行为，我也没有从商业书籍里面获得或收集他们。
read about in a business book, but I
didn't get them from a business book or
any collection of them. For example,
例如，这是我的诫命之一。
here's one of my mantras. If you come
如果你进了我的办公室，告诉我你是一个白痴，我会从嘴里说出的第一句话，绝对是感谢你，很可能会来到桌子旁，给你一个拥抱。
into my office, and you tell me I'm an
idiot, I will say the first words out of
my mouth, will absolutely be thank you,
and very likely I will come around the
table and give you a hug. Because if you
因为如果你不这样做，那可能是那个人最后一次向你说这种事，也可能是你最后一次从你的团队中听到这种事，你以后再也无法了解这样有价值的事了。
don't do that, that will be the last time
that person ever says anything hard to
you, and probably the last time anyone in
the organization ever says anything hard
and therefore important for you to know,
to you. But that's an observation about
但这是在观察人们以及他们如何正常运作的。
humans and like what how they operate. So
所以，我强烈认为，从努力工作中有很多可以学习的东西，面对你长久以来都是错了的事实，因为我们长久以来都错了，因而的确需要听从周围人的意见。
I strongly believe that there's a ton
that can be learned from working hard,
being open to the fact that you're wrong
a lot of the time, because we're all
wrong a lot of the time, and really
listening to the people around you. They
他们有很多可以教你的。
have a lot to teach you. So that doesn't
所以我不是说不要读书，我认为你可以通过你周围百分之一的信息里面改善自己，当然只听从百分之一的有一点理想化。
mean never read any books, but I think
that the idea that you can somehow
program yourself by cleverly picking the
one percent of the fire hose of data
that's coming at you, and only listen to
that one percent, is a bit of a fantasy.
>> Thank you. >> Yeah. >> My question is a little
>> 谢谢。>> 是的。>> 我的问题和这个有点相关，所以，这就像人与人之间在炉边聊天是么？
bit in line with that, so that's a
fireside chats or personal questions,
Okay? I think. So obviously you are [inaudiable]
我认为，很明显你[？]灵感，在你所做的事情上取得了很大成功，在这段时间里，你做了什么，有什么是你必须停下来的，或者你不得不牺牲的？
inspiration and very successful what
you are doing, is there anything you had
to stop doing or anything you had to
sacrifice doing during that time?
>> Yeah I mean I've certainly had to
>> 是的，我是说我牺牲了很多，其中一些对我来说特别难，例如，我是一个大家都喜欢的人。
sacrifice a lot of things, but a few of
them that have been particularly hard
for me, for example, I'm a people pleaser.
I like to resolve conflict, and I'm
我喜欢解决冲突，我的身体你知道，生病可能是夸张，但是与其他人对抗会让我不舒服。
physically feel you know, sick might be
an exaggeration, but uncomfortable when
people around me fight. Even if they work
即使他们为了我工作，我也感觉不好。
for me, I feel bad about it. Obviously,
很明显，因为我无法和人直接冲突，这又对于我这样一个组织管理者是很中重要的，所以我能做这件事是很重要的。
that's totally dysfunctional for me to
be running an organization when I can't
be direct and have conflict with people,
it's really important that I'd be able
to do that. So that's an example of
所以，这有一个例子，当我有箴言或同事情感时，我要如何去做，事实上，让我去做，赶快解决。
something that I have learned how to do
when I have mantras and structures for
emotional structures, that to get me to
do it, and to do it quickly, in fact. But
但当我这样做时，我仍感觉不是很好，我希望我没有把书生气带出来，事实上，我并没有花很多时间在这些事上，这是我的另一个牺牲品。
it still doesn't feel very good when I
do it, and that's the sort of thing I
kind of wish I didn't come out
card-carrying nerd, and yet, I don't
actually spend very much in my time on
those things, that's another sacrifice. I
我想快点实现这些想法，想一些新的东西。
want to end up actually tinkering and
like thinking some the new stuff. I'm an
我是一个企业家，我想在X上运行一个项目，事实上，我不想要我现在的工作了。
entrepreneur I went to like actually run
one of the projects at X, there's a
real sense in which I actually don't
want the job that I have. The reason that
这样做的原因是我相信我在培养一群人，这在其他地方是不可能发生的，这给了我一个真实的目标。
I'm doing it, is because I believe that
I'm nurturing this group of people and
making something possible that wouldn't
be possible otherwise, and that gives me
a real sense of purpose. Even though on a
即使在日常的基础上，对我来说也不是有趣的。
day-to-day basis, it's kind of not what
would be most fun for me. So that's
所以，这是另一个例子。
another example. >> Thank you. >> Hi Sebastian. Hi
>> 谢谢。>> 你好，Sebastian。你好，Astro。
Astro. I'm curious is if you think that
我好奇的是，如果你认为有机会去建一家创业公司，
there is a opportunity to create a
start-up around. Like a dating
就像一个使用机器学习和AI的约会应用，因为我们都知道离婚在我们国家是一个巨大的问题。
application that uses machine learning
and AI, because we all know divorce is like
a giant problem in our country. But maybe
或者说使用谷歌眼镜或其他东西能够建立更完美的匹配。
that uses like Google glass or something
to create perfect matches. Or do you think...
或者，你认为...
>> I am totally letting Sebastian
>> 我完全赞同Sebastian回答这个问题。
take this one. >> Great question! >> Haha.
>> 很棒的问题。>> 哈哈。
>> Sorry what was the question? >> Build it.
>> 抱歉，问题是什么？ >> 建立它。
Do you think a start, there could be
你认为，可以像Tinder那样使用使用机器学习和AI可以创造一个完美的关系，所以你们未来就可以避免离婚了。
like a start-up, kind of like Tinder
that uses machine learning and AI to
create like perfect great relationship
so you can avoid divorce in the future.
>> So let me just answer
>> 所以，让我从不同角度回答一下。
this differently. The number of emails I
由于一些简单的原因，我收到的大多数邮件都来自于德国，表明，因为德国的电视台，一些人们新潮的设计解决了天气变化，回过头看意义是巨大的。
get, for every stupid reason, mostly from
German, stands out because there was in
German television, some futuristic show
of people who build contraptions that
solve climate change and make clocks go
backwards is huge. And sometimes drive we
有些时候我们过于关注人们在创造新事物上面所花费的了。
nuts to see their people like spend so
much time inventing things. I look at
我看着他们并问，为什么？可能，我的意思是说离婚可能是一件好事。
them and say, why? Maybe, I mean fixing
divorces might be a good thing. But what I often
但我经常发现，人们常被技术所吸引。
find, is that people are taken by a
technical idea. They find whatever
他们发现无论什么关系都可以联系起来。
the sake combined. I'm going to pull your
我把它拉长了和你说，你说使用机器学习的Tinder。
long to say, you say Tinder with machine
learning. It's a technical idea, but for
这是一个技术创意，但对我来说，第一步是思考问题。
me, the first step is always to think
about the problem. So to give an example,
举个例子，我有很多机器人学家同事，其中一些人很突出，没有人会教条的认为世界上所有问题都可以用机器人解决。
I have a lot of robotics colleagues, some
very prominent one on the room here, and
any robotics professor takes the dogma
that all problems in the world are
solved by robots. Right? So you'd go for
对么？举个例子，我会说创造一个类人机器人，比如，做点什么呢，好吧，老人护理怎么样。
example, and would say, I build humanoid
robots, and what can they do, well, how
about elderly care. All of Japanese
我已经[?]做的所有日本机器人，像他们这样已经做了20年，建立人类机器人，因为建立这样的人类机器人是有用的，对么？
robotics I have [inaudible] does, is like
that they have done it for 20 years, put
a human robots, because since the building
human items must be useful, right? And it
它必须对某事有用，适用于任何事。
must use for something, so use for
everything. Let me find the most useful
我发现的最有用的事是日常护理。
thing is a daily care. And a company
一家公司找到我，你认为我开一家两条腿的机器人老人护理公司的话，有什么建议呢？
come to me and say, what do you think about if I
can start a company on robots for
elderly care, they have two legs. And
很明显，听起来不错；让我们稍稍跑题一下。
they're obviously, that sounds great,
let's do one little excursion, okay?
Suppose you want to solve the elderly
假设你想解决一个老人护理产品项目的问题，那么不论对象是什么，你都要想着去解决。
care product project problem, the ones
you want to solve,
whatever that one is. Let's think what's
让我们来想想这个问题最好的解决方法，它仍涉及到你公司的机器人，对吧？
the best solution for that problem, if it
still involves the robots inside your
company. All right? So, suppose you're
所以，假设你要去解决你们国家的离婚问题，你真的想去解决它，让离婚变少，不论出于什么原因，让我们来思考一下这个问题最好的解决方案。如果你提出来在Tinder上应用机器学习，那么建立它。
going to solve the divorce problem in
this country, you really want to solve it,
went fewer divorces, say for whatever
reason, then let's take out what is the
best solution with this problem, and if
you come up and think it's machine
learning on Tinder, then, bulid it.
>> I think that's a fine answer. I would also
>> 我认为这是一个很棒的答案。我也会这么说，你知道的，机器学习和Tinder可能不会在我们的X项目中，但一般在X中的项目会说，你需要在这个项目里花多久，多快来解决这个问题，并与其他人讨论？
say that, you know, machine learning and
Tinder might not make our list at X, but
the general answer at X would be, how
fast, how long does it take for you to
think about it, and talk to people? And
你需要多久才能制作一个原型呢？
how long does it take for you to make a
prototype of it. Because if you can make
如果说你原型做的很快，那么正确的答案可能就是，不用担心，就像做它一样，尝试着做一下。
a prototype of it really fast, the right
answer might be, don't worry about it,
just like make it and try it. You'd be
你还会惊讶于你所做的和尝试的，就像超新星一样，你不必有一个解决，我们就像其他人一样不了解这个事物。或者最终事实证明这不是一个好的点子，这是发现它不是一个好点子最快的方法。
amazed what making it and trying it, like
maybe it's going to go supernova and you
don't have to have these arguments, with
idiots who don't understand it like us,
or maybe it turns out that it's
actually not a good idea, and then
that'll be the fastest way to discover
that it's not a good idea. So that's not
所以这并不总是正确的事，但是你听起来原型化很快，但是你最起来可能会更快，而不是要弄清楚你是对是错。
always the right thing to do, but that
one sounds like you could prototype
something so fast that it might actually
be faster to just make it, instead of
trying to figure out whether you're
right or not. >> Unfortunately,
>> 不幸的是，我们马上要结束来了。
unfortunately we run out of time. A few
只剩下几分钟了。
seconds left. Astra it has been... >> Great.
Astra已经...>> 很棒。
Thank you. I want to end by saying that,
谢谢你。 我想以这个结尾，
>> Don't listen. >> That just so funny that's
>> 别听。>> 只是娱乐一下，那确实是我正要说的，很早以前，当我开始X项目时，我向Sebastian报告了，他同意了，所以他是我的领导，我真的很尊敬你，Sebastian。
exactly what I was going to say, so when
I started at X a long time ago, I
reported to Sebastian, and he gave me, so
he was my manager, and I really admire
you, Sebastian. And I just want to leave
我自是想把这些人留在我想的地方，你知道这是个玩笑，我要说的是，一半是要取笑你，但是我也很尊敬他们，我知道你说真诚的意思。
these guys with something that I think
about, and I know you said it
tongue-in-cheek, and I'm going to say it,
partly to tease you, but I also mean it
sincerely to them, and I know you meant
it sincerely to me. The first and
Sebastian是第一个给我认真反馈的人，正如我的主管一样，不要听你的主管。
only really sincere feedback that
Sebastian ever gave me,
as my manager was, don't listen to your
manager. >> And you were good at it.
>> 你很擅长它。
You were good at it. >> And,
你很擅长它。 >> 想不到的是，这个反馈对我是如此的重要，它让我坚持了下来，这也是我为什么尊敬你的原因。
ironically, that was such important
feedback for me, that it's really stuck
with me, and it's part of why I admire
you. Thank you for being a guide for me,
谢谢你引领我，引领我们。
and for all of us. >> My manager sits over
>> 我的主管就坐在那，我可以看到他有多沮丧。
there, and I can see how he's cringing
request. >> Haha. >> Exactly what to do.
>> 哈哈。>> 是的。
>> Thank you, Sebastian!
>> 谢谢你，Sebastian!
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢你。